前情提要
Previously on "grey's anatomy"...
Izzie得了四期转移性黑色素瘤
izzie has stage iv metastatic melanoma
已扩散至脑部 肝部和皮肤
that has spread to her brain, liver and skin.
是他先出手
He threw the first punch.
我该和他谈谈?
I should talk to him?
- Torres先生  - 她是我的宝贝女儿 George
-Mr. Torres  -She's my  only little girl, george.
只要你伤害她...
-The minute  you hurt her--
我订婚了
I'm engaged.
我和Owen分手了
I broke up with owen.
对外科医生来说
defeat isn't an option...
失败不予考虑
not for surgeons.
不到最后一刻决不放弃
We don't back away from the table  till the last breath's long gone.
"晚期病人"是挑战
"Terminal's" a challenge.
"危重病人"是早起的动力
"Life-threatening's" what gets  us out of bed in the morning.
我们不轻易胆怯
We're not easily intimidated...
不畏首畏尾
we don't flinch...
不打退堂鼓
we don't back down...
更不轻易投降
and we certainly don't surrender...
至少对工作而言
not at work anyway.
我不戴戒指你不介意?
Does it bother you that  I don't want to wear it?
因为...
Because I...
我也可以戴
I could.
不用 你天生不是戴戒指的人
I don't want you to wear  it. You' not a ring bride.
怎么了?
What?
我也不喜欢...
I'M... not really A...
教堂婚礼或华丽丽的婚纱
church-wedding bride or a  poofy-white-dress bride either.
那我们就在花丛中赤果果地结婚吧
We'll get naked and get  married in a field of flowers.
我才不要赤果果
I'm not a naked bride.
要不穿手术服吧
What about scrubs? We  can get married in scrubs.
总算有种我喜欢的结婚方式了
Ooh, now there's a wedding I could get into.
要出门了
We gotta go.
我让Izzie帮忙筹备婚礼
so I told izzie she could  help out with the wedding.
这样她就不用躺着胡思乱想
Helps keep her mind off of everything.
我会告诉她穿工作服  和不去教堂的想法
And I'll tell her about the  scrubs and the no church.
简单的婚礼就行
I guess we have a  theme-- simplicity.
或许他们会用手术刀和止血钳给你做花束
you know, maybe they could make you a bouquet of scalpels and clamps.
那挺有趣 我先问下Izzie
Oh, yeah, that would be fun. I think I would have to run it by izzie first.
好吧
Yeah.
我没有任何感受
I don't feel anything.
什么都没?
Nothing?
没有愤怒?
No anger?
幸福?
Happiness?
苦恼?
Unhappiness?
内疚?
Guilt?
幸存的内疚感?
Survivor's guilt?
这在退伍军人中很常见
You know, it's very  common with veterans.
与我的参军无关
It's not about my platoon.
你将情绪置于一边太久了
You have shoved your  feelings aside for so long.
你必须认领回来
I'm asking you to claim them.
Owen...
And, owen...
这与你的参军密不可分
this is about your platoon.
我来这是因为我想掐死女朋友
it's about the fact that I tried  to choke my girlfriend to death.
你认为我的参军感受
What, are you saying the way I feel about my platoon
和对Cristina的感受是一样的?
and  the way I feel about what hapned with cristina are the same?
它们不一样
They're not the same.
既然你无法说出什么感受  你又怎么知道?
Well, how will you know if  you can't name those feelings?
那不是...
That's not what it'S...
是...
it'S...
我不知道
I don't know.
你们不派送婚纱是什么意思?
what do you mean, you  don't deliver dresses?
只能试穿不能送?
Just to try on?
不 我不能去
No, no, no. I-I can't come in.
我得了癌症
I-I have cancer.
必须卧床等死
I'm--I'm bed-bound  and dying.
太好了 我会把我要的传真过去
fabulous. I will fax you my choices.
嗨
Hi.
你们要啥? 血液? 尿液?
Uh, what do you need-- blood,  pee? What can I get you?
不用 我们只是来看看你化疗情况
No, just checking in on you.  See how the chemo's sitting.
我没事
Fine.
没有呕吐
I haven't puked yet
Mer的婚礼也进展不错
and I'm making  major progress on mer's wedding.
你该好好休息
You should really take it easy.
化疗会消耗很多体力
The chemo's gonna take a lot out of you.
我倒下了再通知你
I'll let you know if I hit the wall.
你好 是的
Hello. Hi, yes.
我想谈谈花饰
I wanted to discuss,  um, flower arrangements.
她必须保存体力
she needs to save her energy.
这不是单纯的化疗  是高剂量的白细胞介素-2
This isn't just chemo.  It's high-dose I.L.-2.
用来使身体系统自我攻击
It's designed to make  the body attack itself.
她现在还能走动 但好景不会长
she's walking around now,  but it's not gonna last.
会有血压下降
Her blood pressure's gonna tank
寒颤恶心
she'll  be shaking with chills, she'll be nauseous.
甚至可能心脏病发作
She might even have a heart attack.
相信我 不出几小时...
believe me, a few hours from now...
她将会痛不欲生
izzie stevens is gonna  wish she were dead.
-=伊甸园美剧 http://sfile.ydy.com=-  荣誉出品  本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=www.ydy.com/bbs=-  Proudly Presents
-=YTET-伊甸园字幕组=-  翻译: 马大大 巴黎 翔崽 小跑步的熊 lemon虹 婵婵 托尼拖泥  校对: 蓉蓉 王棫垚  时间轴: 马大炮  720P调: tw612
-=www.ydy.com/bbs=-
医人当自强 第五季  第20集 向爱投降
greys.anatomy.  Season 5 Episode 20
他到了吗?
hey, he here yet?
如果你是说Calliope的爸爸
If you're talking about calliope's  dad
那我不知道
then the answer is, I don't know.
我不会见他
'Cause I'm not going to meet him
我们才开始约会 见家长还为时过早
because we  just started dating and it's way too soon.
Torres也这么想?
And torres is okay with that?
这是她的想法
Yeah, he, her idea.
反正他来一天就走
The man's  here for one day, then he's gone.
不必紧张
No muss, no fuss.
跑 要命就快跑
run. Run for your life.
什么意思?
What do you mean, run for my life?
爸!
Dad!
给我一个不立刻做掉你的理由
Give me one reason I  shouldn't kill you right now.
- 爸 住手  - 他居然出轨
-Dad, stop it.  -He committed adultery.
谁没出过? 离婚前我还和他睡过
Who hasn't? I slept with  him before we were divorced.
理论上 不只George一人出轨
So technically, george isn't  the only one who cheated.
天啊
oh, god.
给我一个不立刻做掉你的理由
Give me one good reason I  shouldn't kill you right now.
Mark Sloan 幸会
Mark sloan. Pleasure to meet you.
爸 Mark只是朋友
Dad, mark is just a friend.
我现在很幸福
I--I'm happy now, okay?
在和别人约会
I'm--I'm  dating someone now, and I'm happy, okay?
你开始约会了?
So you're dating again?
很不错 这才正常
Well, that's good. That's healthy.
我想见见追你的男士
I'd like to meet this  new gentleman suitor.
可以啊 不过
Yeah. Yeah, no.
"他"是这里的医生 忙得很
sh--they're pretty busy,  'cause they're a doctor here.
但...
But, um...
你会喜欢"他"的
you would love them.
你会喜欢"他"的 因为
You'll love them, because
"他"聪明幽默帅气
they're smart and funny and both handsome
英俊漂亮 而且支持我
and--and--and beautiful  and--and very supportive.
爸...
daddy...
求你别生气
please be okay with this.
爸...
Dad...
这位是Arizona Robbins
this is arizona robbins.
她就是我的约会对象
This is who I'm dating now.
真心希望你不会
And I really hope you draw the line
把女人也按倒在墙
at throwing women against walls.
你呼我
you paged me.
司机面部撞到侧车窗
Driver's face went through a side  window.
我想你会有兴趣
Thought it'd be your cup of tea.
没错 无论谁
Right you are, Whoever
什么状况?
what do you got?
Anthony Meloy
Anthony meloy
32岁 男
Anthony meloy, 32-year-old male
步行时撞上车  左臂有伤 脸部身体均受创
pedestrian with  a left arm injury and ro rash to his face d torso.
生命体征稳定
Stable vitals in the field.
撞车后 倒在街上
Landed on the street after  he was hitby the driver.
我没撞他 是他冲向我的
I didn't hit him. He  jumped in front of me.
Dan Gates 和Maloy先生撞上后
Dan gates--swerved after he didn't hit  Mr. Maloy
突然转向 撞上电话线杆
and sideswiped a telephone po.
腹部疼痛
He's complaining of abdominal pain.
并且左耳出血
Also, he has blood coming  out of his left ear.
他不知从哪冒出来的 不是我的错
He came outta nowhere.  It wasn't my fault.
你们最好给那混蛋做个酒精测试
You better give that son of  a bitch a blood alcohol test.
他开车像个疯子一样
He was driving like a madman.
少来 他在撒谎
Okay, now he's just lying.
我撒谎? 你说我撒谎?
Oh, I'm lying? I'm lying?
Maloy先生 请保持镇定
Mr. Maloy, try to stay still.
无头部受创迹象
There's no signof head trauma.
检查另一个  我先带走这个
Check  out the other guy, I got it from here.
走
let's go.
- 等下 我需要检查他的伤口  - 到里面再说
-Wait, I need to look at his injuries.  -When we're inside.
- 酒鬼!  - 骗子!
-Drunk!  -Liar!
- 可悲  - 混球
-Pathetic.  -Ass.
我只是开车去银行
I was just driving to the bank.
突然 这家伙就冲向了我的车
Next thing, this--this guy  jumps in front of my car.
跌跌撞撞地
Whack job.
先生 请抬下眉毛
Sir, can I get you to move your eyebrow?
我没法检查他耳朵 你让下行不行?
I can't examine his ear.  Would you get out of the way?
- 你不能等等?  - 你就不能...
-Could you just wait?  -Could you just...
左上部有游离液体
free fluid in the upper left quadrant.
Grey 安排CT
Grey, schedule a stat C.T.
你感觉怎样 Maloy先生?
How are you doing, Mr. Maloy?
手臂痛死了 其它都还好
My arm's killing me,  but otherwise, I'm fine.
肱骨有压痛和淤伤
He's got tenderness and bruising over his  humerus
但外周血管脉搏良好
but he's got good peripheral pulses.
做个全身检查
We should do a full workup.
O'malley 检查完向Karev汇报
O'malley, check in with karev once you've  assessed, let him know what you find.
等等 我向Karev汇报?
Wait. I'm, uh, reporting to karev?
今天他负责急诊
He's overseeing the pit today.
- 没问题吧 Karev?  - 当然没有
-You good with that, karev?  -Oh, yes, sir.
如果有事 我在手术室
I'll be in the O.R. If you need me.
去吧
Off you go.
见Callie父亲  根本不在今天的日程安排中
Meeting callie's dad was so  not on the agenda for today.
他一看就是那种
I mean, he seems like the kind of man
见女儿女友前得有心理准备的人
who needs a little  preparation before meeting his daughter's girlfriend.
你真该看看他那表情 我...
but you should've seen the  look on his face when I--
够了 你别这样
okay, can you stop doing that thing?
- 哪样?  - 跟我说私事
-What thing?  -That "telling me your business" thing.
今天我休息  我只是来观摩你做胃底折叠术
It's my day off. I'm just here to  watch you do the fundoplication.
我查过你的日程
You know what? I checked your schedule.
你这周工作了90小时
You worked a 90-hour week
你该回家睡觉 或者带孩子
You should be  at home sleeping or playing with your kid.
好了 你也别这样
Okay, you can stop  doing that thing, too.
儿科很辛苦
It's just that peds can be tough.
不利于家庭维系
And it can be hard on a family.
我家没问题 老公非常支持
Not mine. my husband is very supportive.
他...
He is...
迫不及待希望我来儿科
can't wait for me to  start my fellowship.
- 他还不知道 是吧?  - 嗯
-He doesn't know, does he?  -No.
为什么?
Why?
Robbins医生  Jessica痉挛发作 无法呼吸
Dr. Robbins, it's jessica. She just  had a seizure.  She can't breathe.
她患有家族黑蒙性白痴症 需要呼吸口罩
She's got tay-sachs. We  need to get a mask on her.
加到15升
crank it up to 15 liters.
亲爱的 没事了 坐起来
I know, honey. All right.  Sit up.
没事 亲爱的 没事
You're okay, honey. You're okay, honey.
只需要试着呼吸
you just need to breathe.
慢慢地
Slow, slow.
很好 你已经好多了
That's good. That's good.  You're getting better.
慢慢地 好
slow, slow. Okay.
脑部无血块
there's no blood in the brain.
颧上颌综合症 颞骨骨折 耳鼓破裂
Z.M.C. Fracture of the temporal  bone, ruptured ear drum.
预订手术室
Book us an O.R.
别急 Grey医生
Uh, not so fast, Dr. Grey.
这是Gates先生 病人也有名字的
Mr. Gates-- the patient has a name
他面部神经受创 说明什么?
also  has an injured facial nerve, which means what?
说明Gates先生还需要神经修复
That Mr. Gates will  also need a nerve repair.
在Sloan医生的听骨链重建术  之前还是之后?
Does that take place before or after  Dr. Sloan's ossicular reconstruction?
- 之前  - 错
-Before.  -Incorrect.
因为你得检查伤口找寻骨头碎片
Because you'll have to explore  the wound for bone fragments,
更别提要治疗他的传导性失聪
not to mention reversing  his conductive hearing loss.
所以我才要你马上预订手术室 Grey医生
Which is why I need you to  book me that O.R. Now, Dr. Grey.
如果病人面部瘫痪
Look, if this patient has facial paralysis
是否只有一只耳朵听得见就不重要了
it  won't matter if he can hear out of one ear or not?
我说得没错吧 Grey医生?
Am I right, Dr. Grey?
- Grey医生?  - Lexie?
-Dr. Grey?  -Lexie?
- Grey医生?  - 我觉得你俩都很棒
-Dr. Grey?  -I think you both are amazing doctors.
- 你说你是在人行道上被车撞的?  - 对
-you said the car hit you while you were in the crosswalk?  -Yeah.
你检查完没? 我得走了 行不?
Look--look, are you almost done?  'Cause I-I need to go, all right?
还没
Uh, no.
得等警察来 他们要录口供
because, uh, we need to wait for  the police. They need a statement.
有必要么 我是说...
Is that really necessary? I mean...
我把名字电话留下 不行么?
I could just give you my name  and phone number, you know?
就等1分钟 好吗?
I just need to-- I just need you  to wait here for one minute, okay?
- 好  - 谢谢
-Yeah.  -Thank you.
Alex
Alex.
我要请心理医生会诊Maloy
I need to order a psych  consult for Mr. Maloy.
他自称走路时被撞
As walking when the car hit him
但伤情表明并非如此
but the pattern  of his injuries aren't consistent with it.
而且 他有点激动
Plus, he's acting a little agitated.
也许因为他刚被车撞了
Maybe because he was hit by a car.
或者因为你是他医生
Or 'cause he has you as a doctor.
不管什么原因 你都得安排他出院
Either way, you need to discharge him
我们还有很多更严重的病人
because  we have lot of other patients with worse injuries.
如果他离开了 伤害到自己  那都是你的错
If he leaves and he hurts  himself, it's on you.
好吧 就安排个愚蠢的会诊
Fine, get your stupid consult.
但如果有人因为没床位而死去
But if someone in that waiting room dies  because we don't have a bed
那都是你的错
that's on you.
我听说有喜事临门
I hear congratulations are in order.
- 什么?  - 订婚啊
-What?  -The engagement.
我们西雅图仁爱自己人的婚礼
Our very own seattle grace wedding.
我真为你俩高兴
I couldn't be happier  for the both of you.
谢谢 主任 你有任务给我吗?
Thank you, sir. Did you  have an assignment for me?
婚纱
Dresses
什么?
I'm sorry?
Stevens把病房变成了婚礼用品专卖店
Stevens has transformed her  room into a bridal boutique.
去吧 试婚纱去
So go, try on dresses.
这是命令
That's an order.
你不是不想穿婚纱的么
I didn't think you wanted to wear a wedding dress.
是啊
I don't.
他怎么会知道我们订婚了
How does he even know we're engaged?
Richard是我哥们
Richard's my friend.
又不是他订的婚纱
He's not the one that ordered the dress.
你要是不想穿婚纱 自己去和Izzie说
If y't don to wear a  wedding dress, talk to izzie.
是啊 她手臂打着点滴
Oh, yeah. As the chemo  drips into her cancer-y arm,
眼睛可怜地看着我
and she looks at me  with those cancer-y eyes,
眼眸中闪烁对婚礼的热爱
those cancer-y, wedding-loving  eyes...
坚强点
be strong.
咱俩会被粉裙伴娘包围
We will have bridesmaids in pink taffeta
你头戴礼帽 身穿礼服
and  you will be wearing a top hat and a morning coat
再配上"迎风而翔"的婚礼歌曲
and somebody will be singing  "wind beneath my freakin' wings.
要不我去跟她说
" You want me to talk to her?
显然 礼服是免不了了
Apparently a morning  coat is nonnegotiable.
还有 咱还得腾点时间学跳舞
Also, we have to make time  for ballroom dancing lessons.
你知道 我没有刻意去追求一段感情
just so you know, I wasn't  looking for a relationship.
无论与谁 不管男女
Not with anyone  - a he or a she.
但是...
But...
它就这样自然地发生了
it just happened.
而且...
and, uh...
和她在一起 感觉很好
it feels good with her.
很自在
It feels easy and, uh...
很舒服
comfortable.
我很幸福
I'm saying I'm happy.
我还没心甘情愿承认幸福过吧
When have you ever heard  me willingly admit that?
当我们一家人生活在一起时
When you lived at home  with your mother and me.
那时的你 也很幸福
you were happy then.
没错 但那时我才12岁 很容易幸福
yeah, well, I was 12.  It didn't take much.
今天和我回家
You'll fly home with me today.
我去和主任说 把情况说明
I'll talk to the chief and  explain the circumstances.
什么
What?
老爸 不要 我不要回去
No. No, dad, no. I'm  not moving back home.
别担心 一切都会好起来的
Don't worry. Everything's gonna be okay.
现在就很好啊
E-everything  is o-okay.
家族黑蒙性白痴具有致命性
Tay-sachs is always fatal in  children
多发于4至5岁的儿童
usually by the age of 4 or 5.
她6岁
She's 6.
我一个朋友在为Jessica筹款
I spoke to my friend who's doing the fund-raising for  jessica
他说墨西哥有家医院
and he told me about this place in mexico.
他们实施干细胞治疗试验
And they do experimental  stem cell therapy.
只需要几个星期 等我们筹够了钱
In a couple of weeks,  we'll have enough money to--
Matt  Jessica时间不多了
matt, jessica doesn't  have a couple of weeks.
她可能只能撑几个小时了
I think it's quite possible  she only has a couple of hours.
我们早就多次说过了
We've talked about this.  We've talked about this a lot.
现在 为时已到
And now it's here.
我知道你很难接受
And I know it's hard.
你不可能接受
I know it's impossible.
但是我们已经尽力了
But we've done everything that we can.
你也尽力了
And you have done  everything that you can.
不行
No.
不行 听着
No. Listen.
我们只需要再多一点时间
All we need is a little more time.
如果你看过这些治疗方案...
Look, okay, if you read  about these treatments...
我无意冒犯
I don't mean to insult you.
我知道你也尽力了
I-I know you've done everything.
只要再多给我几天时间
I just need a few more days, okay?
只要再多点时间 她很勇敢
I just need a little more  time. She's a fighter.
她会努力抗争 只要我能把她带到那里
You know that she'll fight.  I just need to get her there.
Matt 她到不了墨西哥的
Matt, she's not gonna make it to mexico.
我真的很抱歉
And I am so sorry.
你现在能为她做的
But the best thing that you can do for her now
就是留在这
is to be here.
不
No!
我不需要你告诉我怎么做
you don't tell me what's best.
不要你管 我自己想办法
You don't tell me. I will find a way.
今晚 我就会把她带到墨西哥
I will get her to mexico tonight.
你就这么放弃她 真可耻
Shame on you for giving up on her.
你真是可耻 Robbins医生
Shame on you, Dr. Robbins.
叫急救车 Izzie Stevens病房
get a crash cart. Izzie stevens' room.
Izzie
Izzie.
什么?
what?
神呐 不好意思啊
oh, my god. I'm sorry.
你真该看看你刚才的表情
You should see your face right now.
彻底抓狂的表情
It's your "totally freaking out" face.
你不是吧? 你在耍我?
re joking? This is a joke?
抱歉 但我真的需要你
I'm sorry. I-I really  did need you, though.
备选礼服都在这儿了
Um, I have all these dresses here
我一直在呼Meredith 让她过来试装
and I keep trying to page meredith to come try them on,
但她都没回复
and she won't answer the page.
你能让她过来么? 她会听你的
So will you tell her to come  in here? She'll listen to you.
你面部神经受损
you have damage to your facial nerve
耳后骨折
and a broken bone behind your ear.
我会修复的
Which I'll repair.
脾脏周围有出血
You also have some bleeding around  your spleen.
我们会进一步观察
We'll keep an eye on it.
还有 你的耳鼓破裂
also, your ear drum is ruptured.
可能导致左耳永久失聪
You might permanently lose  the hearing in your left ear.
我不相信 怎么会这样
Unbelievable. Unbelievable.
那个狗娘养的!
That son of a bitch!
Gates先生 保持冷静对您非常重要
Mr. Gates, it's important  that you try and stay calm.
别跟我说什么保持冷静
No, no, don't tell me to stay calm.
那个狗娘养的迎面向我冲过来
That son of a bitch  dove in front of my car.
就像超人一样
He dove, like he was superman.
连双臂都伸展开了
I mean, he had his-- he had his  arms stretched out and everything.
我正要去银行
I was going to the bank.
我只是...
I was just...
要去银行
going to the bank.
我穿给你看 你不许告诉任何人
if I show you the dress, you can never tell  anyone
因为很糟 真的很糟
'cause it's bad-- really, really bad.
好吧 这是我们的小秘密
Okay, fine. It will  be our little secret.
拍照就不是秘密了!
photos are not secret!
不是还配有头饰的吗?
Isn't there a tiara  that goes along with it?
哦 快戴上 让我看看整体效果
Uh, oh, put it-- put it on  so I can get the full effect.
不要头饰 我说过要简约的
N-no--no tiara.  I told you simple.
宴席就上布法罗鸡翅
It's, you know, buffalo  wings at the reception.
没有布法罗鸡翅
You can't have buffalo wings.
婚宴公司根本不做布法罗鸡翅
Caterers don't even do buffalo wings.
Iz 这是个小型婚礼
Iz, this is a small wedding.
很小型的
Small.
这件礼服太隆重 是给大型婚礼用的
And this is a big dress for a g wedding.
就没一件礼服
Don't you have a dress in your pile
走动时不发出声响的么?
that doesn't  make noise when it moves or stand up all by itself?
你要结婚了 这是个奇迹啊
You're getting married. It's a miracle.
Meredith Grey 黑暗之女  找到了另一半
Meredith grey, child of  darkness, has found someone.
难道不值得庆祝吗?
Don't you want to celebrate that?
这可是你的大喜日子 Meredith
It's your day, meredith.
你不能就只穿件傻啦吧唧的礼服
You can't just piss it away on a stupid slip dress
弄些杂货铺的干酪 把它对付过去
and a cheese tray from the grocery store.
那样我会好伤心的...
that will just make me so sad...
我不想再伤心了
and I don't want to be sad
癌症够让我伤心的了
because I'm already suffering through cancer, and that's sad enough.
好吧 头饰给我
Fine. Give me the tiara.
你就像个公主
You're like a princess.
笑一个
Smile.
他要把我拖回家 拖回家啊
***home. He's dragging me home.
好像我是迷路的小女孩
Como si fuera una niÑa perdida
没法对自己做出成熟的抉择
como si yo no  pudiera hacer decisiones adultas sober mi vida...
没法选择共度余生的人
and who I want to spend it with.
我是说 这是我的人生!
I mean... es mi vida!
看得出来你很郁闷
Well, I-I can see  that you're very upset.
你呼我了 Robbins
You paged me, robbins.
你是她最好的朋友
you're her best friend
我现在完全不知所措
and i  am at a giant loss right now.
更别提 那些重病的孩子...
Not to mention, the  very sick children--
去吧 这里有我
go.I got this.
别飙西班牙语了
Stop speaking spanish.
我一会儿还有个手术
'Cause I have to go to surgery in  a minute
我也听不懂西班牙语
and I don't speak spanish.
我爸要把我带回去
My dad is taking me home.
他在和主任谈话 他要我辞职
He's talking to the chief, and he's making  me quit my job
还要了断我的感情
and quit my relationship,
这段感情他根本不承认
which he has yet to  acknowledge even exists.
你才12岁吗? 告诉他这样做简直是疯了
What, are you 12? Tell him he's crazy.
你不明白的
You don't understand.
他把所有事情都给我安排好
There isn't anything he  hasn't done for me, okay?
所有事情
Nothing.
他供我上大学 供我上医学院
He's paid for my college,  he's paid for med school.
我有巨额的信托基金 因为他希望我
I have a huge trust fund because he doesn't want  me
什么都不用操心 专心做个好医生
to worry about anything but being a great doctor.
这个人一生都在全心全意支持我
I mean, the man has done nothing  but support me his whole life.
支持和尊重
Well, supporting someone and respecting
是两码事
someone aren't the same thing.
你得告诉他
You need to tell him that.
哟 看看谁醒了
well, look who's up.
我爸爸呢?
Where's my dad?
他一会儿就回来
He should be here soon.
你感觉怎么样啊?
How you feelin'?
想喝水吗?
You, uh, want some water?
我要爸爸
I want my dad.
没事的
Oh, it's okay.
It's okay.
你知道我儿子害怕时
when my little boy is scared
我会怎么做吗?
you  know what makes him feel better?
我抱着他坐摇椅 来 我示范给你看
When he rocks in the chair  with me. Let me show you.
来吧 好的
Here we go. All righty.
坐摇椅咯 小宝贝
Oh, there we go, sweetie.
瞧 他就喜欢这样
See, he likes this.
他很喜欢
He likes this a lot.
"Joe之家"的干酪三明治来了
Got you the cheeseburger  you wanted from joe'S.
- 你真的要吃这个?  - 真的没事?
-Are you sure about this?  -You really okay?
不恶心?
Not feeling nauseous?
没有 我感觉很好 一点事也没有
No, I feel good. I feel fine.
瞧见没?
See?
嗨
Hi.
薯条 天呐 我超爱薯条
Oh, french fries. God,  I love french fries.
Meredith 出来吧
Meredith, let's go.
穿这件像是在做乳房X光检查
I feel like this dress is giving me  a mammogram.
我的胸都快被挤爆了
It's squishing my boobs.
- 让我看看  - 我要脱了
-Let me see it.  -I'm taking it off.
Iz 你还好吧?
iz, you okay?
- 她喘不过气来了  - Izzie? 给她输氧
-I think she's choking.  -Izzie?  Let's hit her with oxygen.
Izzie 跟我说话 你能说话吗?
Izzie? Izzie, speak to  me.  Can you say something?
Izzie?
我没窒息
I'm not choking.
我闹着玩儿的
I'm joking.
好了 不许那样了 一点也不好玩
Okay, you gotta stop doing  that, 'cause it's not funny.
这样Meredith才会从洗手间出来
It got meredith out of the bathroom
她穿婚纱的样子真漂亮
So I could see her in her dress, and it's gorgeous.
- 跟她说以后不许那样了  - Izzie!
-Tell her she has to stop.  -Izzie!
真浪漫 很漂亮 对不对?
It's very romantic. It's pretty, right?
很漂亮
Pretty.
你竟然邀请她们来看我出丑
And I see you've invited more  people to witness my humiliation.
不是了 Derek和Mark还是互不讲话
No, derek and mark still aren't speaking to each  other
我们要做个6小时的手术
and we're heading into a 6-hour surgery.
除非我能把这个干酪三明治偷偷  带进手术室
So unless I can slip this cheeseburger  into a sterile area
否则真的熬不过去了
I'm not gonna make it.
你能不能跟他们谈谈?
Can you please comeand talk to them?
好吧 你去吧
fine. Okay.  You can go.
Cristina 你能帮她把婚纱脱了么?
Cristina, will you help  her take the dress off?
我先去手术室了
I'll be in the scrub room.
Lexie把薯条都吃了
Lexie just ate all of my fries.
你能再去买点儿吗?
Can you please get me some more?
不错啊 白细胞介素-2一点都没影响到你
Nice. The I.L.-2 isn't  affecting you at all.
医生说如果我们能把她送过去
The doctor said if we can find a way to get her there
他就帮Jessica治疗
he'll treat jessica.
Matt 她一直在找你
Matt-- she's been asking for you.
嘿 宝贝
hey, baby.
你猜怎么着?
Guess what?
我们一起去墨西哥吧
We're gonna go to mexico.
你会爱上那的
You're gonna love it there.
湛蓝的天空 银白的沙滩 还有海水...
The sky is so blue and the sand is white and the water
爸爸 我们能明天再去么?
can we go tomorrow, daddy?
我好累
I'm so tired.
你跟我换个位子吧
why don't you trade places with me?
她要的是你
She-- it's you she wants.
我要机票钱 这样就能出发了
All I need is plane fare, then we'll be on our way.
我可以找人替你一会
B-- I can get someone to relieve you for a while
如果你还想看我做胃底折叠术的话
if you still want to watch me do that fundoplication.
不用了
I'm okay.
在进去做手术之前
okay, before you guys go in there and start cutting on this patient,
你们应该互相道歉
you need to apologize to each other.
即使不是为了病人  就当为了我 或是Lexie
If not for the patient, for me or for lexie.
看看她 吃得脸和臀部都炸开了
Look at her--her face is breaking out, her ass is humongous.
真的 要带束腰带才能穿得上手术服
it's true.I had to get the scrubs with the elastic waistband.
如果你们不马上道歉 她就不做手术了
If you don't apologize right now, she's not scrubbing in.
就是 你们也别想强迫我
I won't, and you can't make me.
这应该是个值得高兴的时刻
This should be a joyful time.
你最好的朋友要结婚了
Your best friend's getting married.
你应该当伴郎
You should be the best man.
主任才是我的伴郎
The chief will be my best man.
什么?
what?
嗨 我的屁股真的...
Hey, is my ass really--
Lexie 能让我们单独谈谈吗
lexie, would you, you know, excuse us, please?
- 主任?  - 伴郎我说了算
-The chief?  -The best man is my choice.
你什么时候才能不再对主任心怀怨恨?
When are you gonna let go of the grudge you have against the chief?
Derek 这人和我妈搞外遇
Derek, the man had an affair with my mother,
毁了我父母的婚姻 还有我的童年
broke up my parents' marriage and basically destroyed my childhood.
还有 你和Mark已经是20年的好朋友了
Meanwhile, you've been best friends with mark for 20 years.
你难道想无端端失去这份友谊吗
And you're willing to row all that away over nothing.
所以不要跟我说什么抛却怨恨
So don't talk to me about holding grudges.
你做到 我就做到
I'll get over mine when you get over yours.
Karev 你在这干嘛?
Uh, what are you doing up here, karev?
我来看看Stevens医生
Uh, I stopped by to see Dr. Stevens.
我正要回急诊
I'm on my way back to the pit.
那个行人怎样了  警察和他谈过了吗?
What happened with the pedestrian? The cops talk to him?
我不知道 没吧
I-I don't know.I-I-I don't think so.
你不知道?
You don't know?
这人可能是想自杀
That guy may have tried to kill himself.
我安排了心理会诊
I called for a psych consult.
你的病人有自杀倾向
You have a potentially suicidal patient
你却在这闲晃?
and you're wandering around up here?
你知不知道撞他的人
Are you aware that the guy that hit him
正被送去手术室?
is on his way to an O.R.?
他情况很糟 可能活不了
He is in terrible shape.He may not live.
- 我...  - 闭嘴!
-I--  -quiet!
如果那个家伙故意跳到车前
If that guy intentionally threw himself in front of that car
所以不要让他离开急诊室
He should pay, so he better not walk out of that E.R.
跑快点 Karev
Move faster, karev.
你要求心理会诊?
You asked for a psych consult?
没错
Yes, I did.
他在哪?
Where is he?
糟糕
Oh, crap.
好哇
wonderful.
- 你把他弄丢了  - 我没有
-You've lost him.  -I have not.
你检查过等候室吗
Have you checked the waiting room?
O'malley  Maloy先生在哪?
O'malley...where's Mr. Maloy?
本来就要给他做心理检测
Psych was supposed to be examining him
而且我还有其他病人
and he's not my only patient.
好极了
nice.
你把他弄丢了
You lost him.
Hunt会气疯的
Hunt is gonna love hearing about this.
你之前都不想给他做心理会诊
You didn't even want e psych consult.
真是搞不懂 我只是... 搞不懂
I don't get it.I just--I don'T.
我也不想否定你
I've tried to give you the benefit of the doubt,
真不明白Hunt看中你哪点
and I j--I don't get what hunt sees in you,
更不明白Izzie看上你哪点
and I sure as hell don't understand what izzie sees.
闭嘴 是我尝试接受你
Oh, shut up.I'm the one who's tried.
Izzie喜欢过你 所以我才尝试
Izzie likeyou, so I've tried.
我想给你最起码的尊敬
I've tried to find one little ounce of respect for you,
但你却把病人弄丢了
but you're the one who lost this guy.
你觉得他有自杀倾向 却没看好他
You thought he was suicidal, and you turned your back.
这不是我的错 我受够你了 O'malley
That's not on me.I'm done with you, o'malley.
我再也不会尊重你了
I'm done trying to respect you.I'm done.
发生了什么事?
What happened?
进行了创伤生命支持 但他...
We did A.T.L.S.Protocol, but he's, uh, he'S...
插了双边胸管 但他还是流血不止
we inserted bilateral chest tubes, but he kept on bleeding out.
心跳减慢 我们给了他阿托品
Then he started bradying down, so we pushed atropine.
失去生命体征后我们开胸
I opened his chest when we lost vitals
发现了断裂不平的肋骨
and found the jagged edge of a rib
肋骨压到突出的大动脉 我用了夹钳
protruding into his ascending aorta, so I attacheda clamp,
然后有了微弱的心跳
and I'm getting some faint heart activity.
你安排好手术室了吗?
You got an O.R.Lined up?
- 二号手术室  - 干得好 O'malley 消毒上台吧
-O.R.Two.  -Good work, o'malley.Scrub .
- 主动脉看起来...  - 行了 Karev
-His, uh, aorta was looking pretty--  -we got it, karev.
我们应该做个中窝开颅术
we should do a middle fossa craniotomy approach.
这儿用金刚钻
Let's get some diamond burrs inere, please.
不用麻烦了 之前我就让他们准备了
Don't bother.I ordered them before we started.
手术室外 我可能不值得信任
I may be irresponsible and untrustworthy out there,
但在这里不是
I'm not in here.
我从来没说过你不值得信任
I never said you were untrustworthy.
你在Lexie身边树了围墙
You put the berlin wall up around lexie.
Meredith叫我这么做的
Well, meredith asked me to.
如果你在意一个人
That's what people do when someone
就会照那个人说的去做
they care about asks them to do something--
你应该照做
they do it
所以我叫你别接近Lexie
which is what you should've done when I asked you to stay away from lexie...
还有Addison 就那事而言
or addison, for that matter.
又来了 Addison 你就会旧事重提
Oh, here we go.Addison-- the only note he can ever play.
我本来打算向你道歉
You know, I was going to apologize for decking you
因为我很内疚
'cause I felt bad.
但现在
But now
我决定好好回想这些旧事
I'm just gonna play it over and over again in my head and really enjoy it.
见鬼 血是从翼静脉丛喷出来的
oh, hell.It's coming from the pterygoid plexus.
- 给我4号缝线  - 给我4号缝线
-Give me a 4-0 vicryl, pl-- get me some 4-0 vicryl.  -Get me the 4-0 vicryl.
夹钳
Get me a clamp.
我受够了
you know what?I'm done.
我放弃
I give up.
即使我没有爱上小Grey
If I hadn't fallen for little grey
你还是会找其他茬
you would've found some otherreason not to respect me.
你总是这样
You always have.
对你来说
To you
我总是你的帮助对象
I'm always gonna be the charity case the shepherds had to take in.
- 我控制住了出血点  - 你已经缝上了?
-I got the bleeder.  -You threw the stitch already?
是的
yeah.
你知道Grey医生在哪吗?
do you know where Dr. Grey is?
不知道 要我呼她吗?
No.Do you want me to page her?
不用 没关系
No, that's okay.
谢谢
thank you.
你拿着牵引器 好么?
Mm- will you hold the retractor, please?
他需要3号普理灵缝线  和聚四氟乙烯移植体
He'll need 3-0 prolene and a gore-tex graft.
我来准备
I'll get it ready.
你很擅长这个
You're good at this.
总是能先想到要做什么
You're thinking ten steps ahead of what you're doing.
不是所有人都能做到这一点
Not many people can do that.
而且情况越糟 你越冷静
And the hairier things get, the calmer you get.
这不是能学到的 而是种天赋
That's not something you learn.It's something you're wired with.
你选择专业了吗?
You chosen your specialty yet?
- 没有 先生  - 选外伤科
-No, sir.  -It's trauma.
不好意思 你要带Torres医生回家?
I'm--I'm sorry.You want to take Dr. Torres home?
我知道我女儿是资深住院医生
Now I recognize that, uh, my daughter's a senior resident
她的成长有你的心血
and you've invested in her education.
我很乐意开张支票
I'm happy to write out a check
给你们医院 金额随你说
for whatever amount as a donation to your hospital.
作为交换条件
In exchange
我希望你能把她转到  迈阿密的圣玛丽医院
I would ask you to transfer her to st.Mary's in miami.
谢谢你这么大方 但恕我冒昧
Uh, I appreciate the offer, sir, but, uh, with all due respect,
你的女儿是成年人了
your daughter is a grown woman.
她知道你来找我谈话吗?
Does she know you're here?
你没有孩子吧?
you don't have children, do you?
没有
No, no. No, I don't.
你肯定没有
No, you don't, no.
因为如果你有...
Because if you did...
就不会说"女儿已经成年了"
"your daughter's a grown woman"
这话一点意义都没有
I mean, that-- that means nothing.
她是我的孩子
She's my child.
就像血管里流淌的血液一样
It's like blood running through your veins.
那种感觉不会消失 永远不会
You don't outgrow it, it never goes away--
爱他们
the love
保护他们不受任何伤害
the need to protect them from everything-- from everything--
甚至不允许他们伤害自己
even fromthemselves.
他们长大后 搬出去住  变成了
They grow up, they move out, they change,
连你也不认识的人
become people you don't even recognize,
他们自己拿主意
make decisions...
我是说...
I mean...
他们认为你不够爱他们
and they think you don't love them
因为你不了解
because you don't understand,
但恰好相反
but it's the opposite.
恰好相反
See, it's the opposite.
你为了他们去奋斗
You fight for them, always.
你从不投降
You never surrender.
当孩子有危险时 你从不投降
When your child is on the line, you never surrender.
我给8个机构打了电话
I called eight organizations
他们有紧急资金提供给候选人
and they have a wait list for emergency funds.
我不知道怎么办 我不知道
I don't know what to do. I just--I don't know--
Smithson先生 不要再做了
Mr. Smithson, it's time to stop now.
也许只要我们去机场
Maybe if we just go to the airport
他们就会让我们登机的
they'll let us on a flight.
为了生病的孩子 他们会同意的
I mean, people do things like that, right? For a sick child, they'll--
- Smithson先生  - 不要
-Mr. Smithson--  -no!
不要叫我放弃
Please don't make me stop, okay?
Please don't make me stop.
我也不想放弃
I wouldn't want to stop either
但Jessica不行了 Matt
but Jessica is terminal, Matt.
再过一会 她心脏就要停止跳动了
In a few minutes, her heart is going to stop.
我可以给她做心脏复苏
Now I can-- I can pump her chest
给她各种各样的药
push all sorts of medicines,
我可以给她呼吸机
I can put her on a ventilator
因为她再也不能自己呼吸了
'cause she'll no longer be able to breathe on her own,
但即使这样 她还是会死的
but even with all of that, she's going to die.
最后握住她的手的人
And the last person who will have had her hands on her,
最后呵护她的人
who will have been able to touch her
可以是我或别的护士
well, it's gonna be me or--or a nurse.
但也可以是你
Or it could be you...
因为你不会希望错过这个时刻
'cause you don't want to miss this.
接下来 她需要她的爸爸
This next part-- she needs her daddy for this part.
爸爸...
daddy...
我们去墨西哥吗
are we going to mexico?
是的
yes
我们要去墨西哥
We're going to mexico...
那里有湛蓝的天空
where the sky is "blue" blue...
银白色的沙滩
and the sand is white...
海水清澈见底
and the water is so clear that you can see all the way to the bottom.
我们要去...
we're going...
只有你和爸爸
just you and me.
没有医生
no more doctors.
不用吃药
No more medicine.
不去医院
No more hospitals.
只有你和爸爸
Just you and me.
你只要放轻松 不久我们就到了
we're gonna go.You just relax.We'll be there soon.
我们在沙滩上玩一整天
and we'll play on the beach all day.
用沙堆城堡
And we'll make sand castles.
我们要去的
We're gog.
很快我们就到了 你会看到的
We'll be there soon.You'll see.
我们会玩得很愉快
And we're gonna have so much fun.
只有你和我
just you and me.
Just you and me.
高压98 低压72
98 over 72.
非常好
That's good.
别这样
Don'T.
不要让我自我感觉良好  因为我一点都不好
Don't try and make me out better than I am, because I'm not.
难受死了
I'm sick.
今天你注射了很多白细胞介素-2
You had an incredibly high dose of I.L.-2 today.
你现在的感觉很正常
This is how you're supposed to feel.
今天我只想翻杂志 订餐饮供应商
All I wanted to do today was flip through magazines and call caterers
叫Grey试穿婚纱 虽然她很讨厌
and make mer try on dresses I knew she'd hate.
我以为会很开心
I thought it would be f-- fun or...
有趣
funny.
本以为能保持早晨起床时的身体状况
I thought I could be the same person I was when I woke up this morning.
但不行
But I'm not.
我就是一个...
I'm just another patient trapped inside...
垂死的癌症患者
a sick, dying, cancer-ridden body.
怎么了?
what happened?
他给我下了最后通牒
He, uh...gave me an ultimatum.
我如果不回家
Said if I didn't come home
他就取消我的信托基金
he'd take away my trust fund...
他要切断给我的资金补助
he'd cut me off.
所以我就和他决断了
So I cut him off.
如果他不能接受真实的我
I mean, if he can't accept me for who I am...
我和他决断了
I cut him off.
你还好吧?
Are you okay?
不好
No.
还行 我也不知道
I mean, yeah.I...I don't know.
我跳到...
I jumped...
她的车前
in front of her car.
而她只是...
And she was just...
想去银行
driving to the bank.
我们说的是Cristina?
We're talking about cristina?
我介入她的生活
I jumped in front of her.
我知道自己没有痊愈
I knew.I knew I wasn't together.
我对她没好处 对谁都没好处
I knew I was no good for her, for anyone.
我毁了她
And I wrecked her.
那...是不可原谅的
And that...is unforgivable.
我无法原谅自己
I don't forgive myself for that.I can't forgive myself for that.
我对此感到羞愧
And I am feeling shameful about that.
这就是我今天的感受 羞愧
That is what I feel today-- shame.
很好
Good.
- 这是个开端  - 怎么能算是开端?
-That's a start.  -How is that a start?
你说出了...
You named it...
你的感受
the feeling.
你扬帆起航前
You have to know what it is
总要明白自己的现状
before you can start to navigate to somewhere better.
他的康复期会很长
he has a long recovery ahead of him.
面神经严重受损
He severely damaged his facial nerves
内耳粉碎 大量出血
shattered his inner ear and lost a great deal of blood.
上帝啊
Oh, my god.
他会好的
but he'll be fine.
他会疼上一阵子 但
He'll be in some pain for a while, but
他会好的
he'll be fine.
上帝啊 谢谢 谢谢你们
Oh, my god.Thank you.Thank you both so much.
谢Sloan医生吧
Thank Dr. Sloan
这种程度的出血  没有几个医生能处理好
That kind of bleed not many surgeons could've handled it.
他救了你丈夫的命
He saved your husband's life.
你现在想看看你丈夫么?
Would you like to see your husband now?
是的 谢谢
Yes, thank you.
你知道这是你第一次表扬我么?
you know that's the first actual compliment you've ever given me?
不是表扬 只是实话实说
It wasn't a mpliment.It was a simple statement of fact.
你干嘛这样
See, why do you do that?
为啥就不能表扬下别人?
Why can't you just give a person a compliment?
如果你强求别人表扬 那就不算表扬了
If you have to ask for a compliment, it's not a compliment.
- 你想要我表扬你么?  - 当然了
Are you asking for a compliment?
那就不能算是表扬了
Then it's not a compliment.
我走之前还能为你做点什么?
Is there anything else you need before I go?
不用了
No.
你想坐一会儿么?
Yowant to sit a while?
不想
No, I do not want to sit.
我在这儿干躺着一天了...
I've been sitting and lying down all day...
- Bailey医生  - 抱着一个孩子
-Dr. Bailey--  -holding a child.
如果我想花一整天来抱孩子
If I wanted to spend the day holding a child,
我就该在家里抱自己的孩子
I would have stayed home to hold my own child.
我今天没做一件和医学有关的事
I didn't do a single medical thing today.
甚至都没给病人贴过绷带
I didn't even put a band-aid on a patient.
我累了...
I'm--I'm just tired.I...
我受够了
I'm done.
你会告诉你丈夫么?
Are you gonna tell your husband?
我该和他怎么说?
At would I tell him?
告诉他不是动动刀这么简单
That it's more than just cutting.
儿科不是动动刀这么简单
Peds is more than just cutting.
你今天是个英雄
And what you did today was heroic.
你知道的
And you know it.
好吧
Okay.
也许我会和他这么说的
Maybe I'll tell him that.
身为医生...
To do our jobs...
我们不能接受失败
we have to believe defeat is not an option...
无论患者多么羸弱...
that no matter how sick our patients get...
你会是个漂亮的新娘
you're gonna make a beautiful bride.
他们都还有希望
There's hope for them.
你今天真厉害 O'malley 胜过了我
You kicked ass today, o'malley.You kicked my ass.
我只是做了应该做的
I just did what I had to do.
不...你今天很棒
No, no.You...you kicked ass.
我做不到
I'm not like that.
我很优秀 但是不能像你那样...
I'm good, but not like you.I'm not...
在压力下超常发挥
good under pressure.
她病得很重
She's really sick--
非常重 我却不擅长处理压力
really sick-- and I'm not good under pressure.
但是即使希望被现实打败
But even when our hopes give way to reality
我们不得不向事实投降
and we finally have to surrender to the truth...
也只意味着我们输了今天的小战役
it just means we've lost today's battle...
能再给我一杯么?
could I have another, please?
而不是明天的战斗
Not tomorrow's war.
我想盛大的婚礼也没那么糟
So I guess a big wedding won't be that bad.
真郁闷 没见到你穿最终选中的那件
I'm just sad 'cause I didn't get a chance to see you in the actual dress.
- 你会见到的  - 怎么见?
-You will.  -How?
我是说 如果Derek和Mark不和好...
I mean, if derek and mark don't make up, how...
你是我妹妹 Lexie
you're my sister, lexie.
你肯定要参加婚礼
You're in the wedding.
我的天
Oh, my god.
我要当伴娘么?
I'm gonna be a bridesmaid?
天啊 我不知道该说什么
Oh, my god.I don't know what to say.
你等着瞧Izzie给你选的衣服吧
Well, you should wait and see what izzie's picked out for you to wear.
到时你就有很多话要说了
And then you'll have plenty to say.
关于投降...
here's the thing about surrender...
- 想喝一杯么?  - 太想了
-do you want one?  -So much.
一旦你投降...
Once you do it...
我们还能赶上看下半场比赛
We can still catch the last half of the game.
我也这么想的
Yeah, that's-- that's what I was thinking.
真正妥协了...
Actually give in...
你会忘记最开始挣扎的原因
you forget why you were even fighting in the first place.
- 你可以不用再吃了  - 感谢上帝
-you can stop eating now.  -Oh, thank god.
-=YTET-伊甸园字幕组=-  翻译: 马大大 巴黎 翔崽 小跑步的熊 lemon虹 婵婵 托尼拖泥  校对: 蓉蓉 王棫垚  时间轴: 马大炮  720P调: tw612
-=www.ydy.com/bbs=-  Proudly Presents